Now that you're a pro at making commits,
الآن وبما أنكم قد أصبحتم محترفين في إجراء التثبيتات،
it's time to level up again.
فقد حان وقت الترقية مجددًا.
This leveling-up is going to be an awesome step that
وسوف يكون هذا الارتقاء خطوة رائعة
will really give you version control superpowers.
ستمنحكم حقًا قدرات خارقة للتحكم بالنسخة.
In this lesson, we'll look at git tag,
في هذا الدرس سوف نركِّز على علامة git
git branch, git checkout and git merge.
وفرع git ومراجعة git ودمج git.
With git tag, you'll be able to add tags to specific commits.
باستخدام علامة git، سوف تتمكنون من إضافة علامات لتثبيتات محددة.
A tag is an extra label for a commit that can indicate useful information,
العلامة هي عنوان إضافي لتثبيت يمكنه أن يشير إلى معلومات مفيدة،
like, this is the beta release.
مثل أن هذا هو إصدار beta.
With git branch, you'll be able to create
وباستخدام فرع git، سوف تتمكنون من
branches that let you develop different features of
إنشاء فروع تسمح لكم بتطوير سمات مختلفة
your project in parallel without getting
لمشروعكم بالتوازي دون
confused as to which commits belong to which feature.
أن يختلط عليكم الأمر فيما يتعلق بأيّ التثبيتات تعود إلى أيّ سمة.
That might sound a bit confusing,
قد يبدو هذا مربكًا بشدة؛
just hang on, and we'll cover it in detail.
انتظروا قليلًا فحسب وسوف نتناوله بالتفصيل.
With git checkout, you'll be able to switch between different branches and tags.
باستخدام مراجعة git، سوف تتمكنون من التبديل بين الفروع والعلامات المختلفة.
Git merge is amazingly helpful,
دمج git مفيد إلى حد مذهل،
because you can use it to take changes on
حيث يمكنكم استخدامه في التقاط الاختلافات
different branches and combine them together automatically.
بين الفروع المختلفة وجمعها معًا بشكل تلقائي.
It's an incredibly powerful feature.
هذه سمة قوية إلى حدٍ لا يُصدق.
The commands we're covering in this lesson will help keep
سوف تساعد الأوامر التي نتناولها في هذا الدرس في إبقاء
your project organized and speed up development.
مشروعكم منظمًا والإسراع من تطويره.
Let's start things out with the easiest command, git tag.
دعونا نبدأ بأسهل أمر، وهو علامة git.